A Register of the Mark V. Vishniak Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence, 1917-1968 and undated. (Box 1)
  - Nol'de, E.B., 1951-1952 (Folder 8: 35)
  - Novak-Deker, N., 1956 (Folder 8: 36)
  - Novitsky, George, 1960 (Folder 8: 37)
  - Novoe Russkoe Slovo, 1945 (Folder 8: 38)
  - Nummy, George M., 1946 (Folder 8: 39)
  - Obolesheff, Theoktist, 1939 (Folder 8: 40)
  - Odarchenko, R., and Gorbett, D.M., 1956 (Folder 8: 41)
  - O'Flaherty, Dennis M., 1966 (Folder 8: 42)
  - Ogg, Frederic A., 1944 (Folder 8: 43)
  - Osokin, Vadim, 1939 (Folder 8: 44)
  - Osorgin, Mikhail, 1938 (Folder 8: 45)
  - Ossoguine, Rashel, 1941-1956
    - 1941-1942 (Folder 8: 46)
    - 1943-1945 (Folder 8: 47)
    - 1951-1956 (Folder 8: 48)
  - Ozols, Charles W., undated (Folder 8: 49)
  - Pachmus, Tamira A., 1967-1968 (Folder 8: 50)
  - Panova P.A., 1945 (Folder 8: 51)
  - Parsons, Steven L., 1967 (Folder 8: 52)
  - Pashutinsky, A., undated (Folder 8: 53)
  - Pastunova, Ekaterina A., 1943-1949 (Folder 8: 54)
  - Pat, 1947 (Folder 8: 55)
  - Pavlovskaya, Taisiia, 1963-1968 (Folder 8: 56)
  - Pavlovsky, Michel N., 1936-1963
    - 1936-1937 (Folder 8: 57)
    - 1938
      - January-April (Folder 8: 58)
      - May-June (Folder 8: 59)
      - July-September (Folder 8: 60)
      - October-December (Folder 8: 61)
    - 1939
      - January-March (Folder 8: 62)
      - April-June (Folder 8: 63)
      - July-December (Folder 8: 64)
    - 1940 (Folder 8: 65)
    - 1941 (Folder 8: 66)
    - 1945-1946 (Folder 8: 67)
    - 1947-1949 (Box-folder 9: 1)
    - 1950-1954 (Folder 9: 2)
    - 1956-1959 (Folder 9: 3)
    - 1960-1961 (Folder 9: 4)
    - 1962-1963 (Folder 9: 5)
  - Pennar, J., 1963 (Folder 9: 6)
  - Petchkovsky, M.J., 1938-1939 (Folder 9: 7)
  - Petouhoff, J., 1955 (Folder 9: 8)
  - Petrov, Vladimir, 1950-1958 (Folder 9: 9)
  - Petrunov, Ivan, 1919 (Folder 9: 10)
  - Pilenko, Sofia, 1955-1957 (Folder 9: 11)
  - Pill, Gertrude, 1946 (Folder 9: 12)
  - Pinson, Koppel S., 1940-1950 (Folder 9: 13)
  - Pipes, Richard, 1945-1947 (Folder 9: 14)
  - Podolsky, Miguel, 1958-1959 (Folder 9: 15)
  - Poliakov, L., 1953 (Folder 9: 16)
  - Poliakov-Litovtsev, S., undated (Folder 9: 17)
  - Poluektov, P., undated (Folder 9: 18)
  - Polushkin, Nikolai S., 1958 (Folder 9: 19)
  - Poore, Francis R., 1942 (Folder 9: 20)
  - Porte, J.V., De, undated (Folder 9: 21)
  - Porter, Scott C., 1946 (Folder 9: 22)
  - Portugez, S., 1940 (Folder 9: 23)
  - Posin, Jack, 1946-1969
    - 1946 (Folder 9: 24)
    - 1955 (Folder 9: 25)
    - 1956 (Folder 9: 26)
    - 1957-1959 (Folder 9: 27)
    - 1961-1962 (Folder 9: 28)
    - 1963-1964 (Folder 9: 29)
    - 1965-1966 (Folder 9: 30)
    - 1967-1969 (Folder 9: 31)
  - Posthumus, N.W., 1967 (Folder 9: 32)
  - Postnikov, S., 1951-1964
    - 1951-1959 (Folder 9: 33)
    - 1960-1961 (Folder 9: 34)
    - 1962-1964 (Folder 9: 35)
  - Pregel, Boris, 1944-1960 (Folder 9: 36)
  - Pregel, S., 1948-1964 (Folder 9: 37)
  - Prendergast, Curtis, 1964 (Folder 9: 38)
  - Prensky, Eva, 1940 (Folder 9: 39)
  - Proskaner, Joseph M., 1946 (Folder 9: 40)
  - Protich, J., undated (Folder 9: 41)
  - Ptashkina, N., 1959 (Folder 9: 42)
  - Pushkarev Serge, 1962 (Folder 9: 43)
  - Rabinovich, D., 1946, 1962 (Folder 9: 44)
  - Radio Liberation, 1957 (Folder 9: 45)
  - Radkey, O., 1958 (Folder 9: 46)
  - Rahn, Alfred H., and Lilly, 1949 (Folder 9: 47)
  - Rappoprt, J.K., 1938-1939 (Folder 9: 48)
  - Raptschinsky, B., 1939 (Folder 9: 49)
  - Ratgaus (Klimenko), T., 1938 (Folder 9: 50)
  - Rausen, Israel G., 1962-1965 (Folder 9: 51)
  - Raycer, Michael S., undated (Folder 9: 52)
  - Reimers, Nikolai A., 1939 (Folder 9: 53)
  - Remizov, A., 1959 (Folder 9: 54)
  - Resnikoff, S., 1959 (Folder 9: 55)
  - Resler, Donald, 1945-1946 (Folder 9: 56)
  - Reswick, William, 1952 (Folder 9: 57)
  - Reuveni, J., 1961-1968 (Folder 9: 58)
  - Richardson, Inez G., 1947-1948 (Folder 9: 59)
  - Richer, Felix, 1937 (Folder 9: 60)
  - Rischin, Moses, 1967 (Folder 9: 61)
  - Ritter, A., 1955 (Folder 9: 62)
  - Robeman, Victor, 1949 (Folder 9: 63)
  - Roberts, Henry l., 1965 (Folder 9: 64)
  - Robinson, Geroid T., 1945 (Folder 9: 65)
  - Robinson, Jacob, 1931-1948
    - 1931-1940 (Folder 9: 66)
    - 1941 (Folder 9: 67)
    - 1942 (Folder 9: 68)
    - 1943-1948 (Folder 9: 69)
  - Rogers, Norman, 1964-1965 (Folder 9: 70)
  - Rodicheva, A., 1929 (Folder 9: 71)
  - Romm, Frieda, 1945 (Folder 9: 72)
  - Rosen, Valentine Snow, 1945 (Folder 9: 73)
  - Rosenfeld, O., 1948 (Folder 9: 74)
  - Rostovtzeff, M., 1938-1940 (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - Roucek, Joseph, 1946 (Folder 10: 2)
  - Roudneff, Vadim V., 1936-1946
    - undated (Folder 10: 3)
    - 1936-1937 (Folder 10: 4)
    - 1938-1939 (Folder 10: 5)
    - 1942-1946 (Folder 10: 6)
  - Rubaschov, A., undated (Folder 10: 7)
  - Rubinstein, J., 1952-1962 (Folder 10: 8)
  - Russkii Nauchnii Institut v Belgrade, 1939 (Folder 10: 9)
  - Rzhevskii, L., 1963 (Folder 10: 10)
  - Sabsay, S., undated, 1964 (Folder 10: 11)
  - Sack, Alexander, J., 1922-1943
    - 1922 (Folder 10: 12)
    - 1940-1943 (Folder 10: 13)
  - Safonov, B., 1963 (Folder 10: 14)
  - Samoiloff, Nicolas, undated (Folder 10: 15)
  - Sauer, S., 1951 (Folder 10: 16)
  - Savin, V., undated (Folder 10: 17)
  - Scher, Marie, undated (Folder 10: 18)
  - Scherf, David, 1957 (Folder 10: 19)
  - Schschkin, M., 1959 (Folder 10: 20)
  - Schults, G., 1963-1967 (Folder 10: 21)
  - Schumer, William, 1947 (Folder 10: 22)
  - Schwarz, Solomon, 1943-1967
    - 1943 (Folder 10: 23)
    - 1944 (Folder 10: 24)
    - 1945-1946 (Folder 10: 25)
    - 1955-1959 (Folder 10: 26)
    - 1961-1962 (Folder 10: 27)
    - 1963-1967 (Folder 10: 28)
  - Selezneff-Skib, L., 1947 (Folder 10: 29)
  - Semiczek, Marian, 1951 (Folder 10: 30)
  - Sergiev, Polien P., 1965 (Folder 10: 31)
  - Sergievsky, N., 1945 (Folder 10: 32)
  - Shapiro, Boris, 1943-1961 (Folder 10: 33)
  - Sharett Yaakov, 1957 (Folder 10: 34)
  - Shaw, Glenn, 1944-1946 (Folder 10: 35)
  - Shebeco, N., 1964 (Folder 10: 36)
  - Shirman, S., 1940 (Folder 10: 37)
  - Shmelev (Chmelev), Ivan S., 1938, 1947
    - 1938 (Folder 10: 38)
    - 1947 (Folder 10: 39)
  - Shneyeroff, M.M., 1955 (Folder 10: 40)
  - Shpolianskii (Don Aminado), Aminad P. and Nadezhda M., 1940-1968
    - 1940-1944 (Folder 10: 41)
    - 1945-1947 (Folder 10: 42)
    - 1948-1950 (Folder 10: 43)
    - 1951 (Folder 10: 44)
    - 1952 (Folder 10: 45)
    - 1953 (Folder 10: 46)
    - 1954-1955 (Folder 10: 47)
    - 1956 (Folder 10: 48)
    - 1957 (Folder 10: 49)
    - 1958-1960 (Folder 10: 50)
    - 1961-1968 (Folder 10: 51)
  - Shtern, S., 1939 (Folder 10: 52)
  - Shub, A., 1963 (Folder 10: 53)
  - Shub, Boris, 1950-1953 (Folder 10: 54)
  - Shub, David, 1942-1967 (Folder 10: 55)
  - Shub, Louis, 1943 (Folder 10: 56)
  - Shubakov, K., 1944 (Folder 10: 57)
  - Shuvalov, Petr, 1968 (Folder 10: 58)
  - Shveitser, M., 1950, 1956 (Folder 10: 59)
  - Sidorov, P., undated (Folder 10: 60)
  - Simkhovitch, Vladimir, 1941 (Folder 10: 61)
  - Skidell, Kieve, 1942 (Folder 10: 62)
  - Skitalets, E.S., 1959 (Folder 10: 63)
  - Skliarenko, S., undated (Folder 10: 64)
  - Slonim, Marc, 1956 (Folder 10: 65)
  - Slutskii, I., 1965 (Folder 10: 66)
  - Smith, L.S., 1946 (Folder 10: 67)
  - Smoliar, M., 1948 (Folder 10: 68)
  - Soiuz Russkikh Evreev, 1955 (Folder 10: 69)
  - Sollogub, N., 1961 (Folder 10: 70)
  - Solntsev, Constantin I., 1947-1958 (Folder 10: 71)
  - Solotarew, W., 1959 (Folder 10: 72)
  - Soloveitchik, Samson, 1940-1968
    - undated (Folder 10: 73)
    - 1940-1944 (Folder 10: 74)
    - 1945 (Folder 10: 75)
    - 1946-1949 (Folder 10: 76)
    - 1954-1960 (Folder 10: 77)
    - 1961-1964 (Folder 10: 78)
    - 1965-1968 (Folder 10: 79)
  - Sorokin, P.A., 1940-1946 (Folder 10: 80)
  - Sosin, Jene, 1957 (Folder 10: 81)
  - Souvarine, Boris, 1938-1959 (Box-folder 11: 1)
  - Spackman, W.M., 1946-1949 (Folder 11: 2)
  - Spiegelstein, Max, 1959 (Folder 11: 3)
  - Spivak, Lawrence, 1947-1948 (Folder 11: 4)
  - Stanka, Vladas, 1967 (Folder 11: 5)
  - Stankevich, V.B., 1920 (Folder 11: 6)
  - Starr, Joshua, 1946 (Folder 11: 7)
  - Staudinger, Else, 1941-1942 (Folder 11: 8)
  - Stearns, Robert L., 1945-1946 (Folder 11: 9)
  - Stein, I.E., 1957 (Folder 11: 10)
  - Steinberg, Julien, 1950 (Folder 11: 11)
  - Steinberg, Samuel., 1944-1964 (Folder 11: 12)
  - Stencel, Z., 1940-1949 (Folder 11: 13)
  - Stepun, Fedor, 1956-1964 (Folder 11: 14)
  - Stevens, Mary H., 1945-1947 (Folder 11: 15)
  - Stoliarsky, Raphael G., 1955-1957 (Folder 11: 16)
  - Stolkind A., 1942-1944 (Folder 11: 17)
  - Stones, Gilbert, 1945 (Folder 11: 18)
  - Strakhanovsky, Leonid I., 1950 (Folder 11: 19)
  - Struve, Gleb, 1939-1969
    - 1939-1949 (Folder 11: 20)
    - 1950 (Folder 11: 21)
    - 1951-1952 (Folder 11: 22)
    - 1955 (Folder 11: 23)
    - 1956 (Folder 11: 24)
    - 1957-1958 (Folder 11: 25)
    - 1959 (Folder 11: 25)
    - 1960 (Folder 11: 26)
    - 1961 (Folder 11: 27)
    - 1962 (Folder 11: 28)
    - 1963 (Folder 11: 29)
    - 1964-1965 (Folder 11: 30)
    - 1966-1967 (Folder 11: 31)
    - 1968-1969 (Folder 11: 32)
  - Sukov, A., undated (Folder 11: 33)
  - Surkov, A.A., 1938 (Folder 11: 34)
  - Sydney, P., 1967 (Folder 11: 35)
  - Swet, Gershon, 1939-1967 (Folder 11: 36)
  - Szeftel, Mark, 1955 (Folder 11: 37)
  - Tallberg, 1958 (Folder 11: 38)
  - Tanis, 1967 (Folder 11: 39)
  - Trasevich, Leo, 1961 (Folder 11: 40)
  - Tarasov, Lev, undated (Folder 11: 41)
  - Tarsaidze, Alexandre G., undated (Folder 11: 42)
  - Tatarinov, V.E., 1941 (Folder 11: 43)
  - Tauberg, Ekaterina, 1938 (Folder 11: 44)
  - Tchernavina, T., 1938-1959 (Folder 11: 45)
  - Tchernoff (Chernov), Victor, 1944 (Folder 11: 46)
  - Tchernovits, C., 1941 (Folder 11: 47)
  - Tchirkin, V., 1949 (Folder 11: 48)
  - Tchitchibabine, A., 1939 (Folder 11: 49)
  - Teitel, J.L., Committee, undated (Folder 11: 50)
  - Ter-Pogossian, Michel, 1938-1966 (Folder 11: 51)
  - Timashev, N.S., 1944-1960 (Folder 11: 52)
  - Time, 1946-1968
    - undated (Folder 11: 53)
    - 1946-1949 (Folder 11: 54)
    - 1950-1958 (Folder 11: 55)
    - 1961-1968 (Folder 11: 56)
  - Timoff, Vladimir V., 1945 (Folder 11: 57)
  - Timkoff, Marina, 1966-1968 (Folder 11: 58)
  - Tishinoff, G., 1945 (Folder 11: 59)
  - Titov, A., 1957 (Folder 11: 60)
  - Torsuev, A., 1938 (Folder 11: 61)
  - Tretiakoff, Victor, 1939 (Folder 11: 62)
  - Trotsky, Il'ia, 1954-1957 (Folder 11: 63)
  - Troyal, Henry, 1939 (Folder 11: 64)
  - Trubetskoi, A., 1961 (Folder 11: 65)
  - Tscherikower, E., 1938-1943 (Folder 11: 66)
  - Tsuzochenko, A., 1951 (Folder 11: 67)
  - Ulanov, B., 1949, 1963 (Folder 11: 68)
  - Ul'ianov, Nikolai A., 1929-1968 (Folder 11: 69)
  - Ulitin, Grigorii, A., 1961 (Folder 11: 70)
  - Ullman, Walter H., undated (Folder 11: 71)
  - Ushakova, O., 1945 (Folder 11: 72)
  - Uvarova, 1949 (Folder 11: 73)
  - Vakar, Nicholas P., 1958-1969
    - 1958-1962 (Folder 11: 74)
    - 1963-1969 (Folder 11: 75)
  - Vassiliev, Sergius A., 1960 (Box-folder 12: 1)
  - Vaudrin, Philip, 1942 (Folder 12: 2)
  - Veisbrem, L., 1938 (Folder 12: 3)
  - Velmine, Anatole, 1948 (Folder 12: 4)
  - Vidness, Maria, 1957 (Folder 12: 5)
  - Vikre, Elizabeth r., 1944 (Folder 12: 6)
  - Vinaver, E., undated (Folder 12: 7)
  - Vishniak, Roman (Folder 12: 8)
  - Vishpitser, M., 1942 (Folder 12: 9)
  - Vodoff, S.A., 1956-1968
    - 1956 (Folder 12: 10)
    - 1957 (Folder 12: 11)
    - 1958 (Folder 12: 12)
    - 1959 (Folder 12: 13)
    - 1960 (Folder 12: 14)
    - 1961 (Folder 12: 15)
    - 1962 (Folder 12: 16)
    - 1963 (Folder 12: 17)
    - 1964 (Folder 12: 18)
    - 1965 (Folder 12: 19)
    - 1966 (Folder 12: 20)
    - 1967 (Folder 12: 21)
    - 1968 (Folder 12: 22)
  - Voitinskaia, Emma, 1942 (Folder 12: 23)
  - Vol'skii, N., 1938-1962
    - undated (Folder 12: 24)
    - 1938 (Folder 12: 25)
    - 1939 (Folder 12: 26)
    - 1949 (Folder 12: 27)
    - 1950-1955 (Folder 12: 28)
    - 1956-1957 (Folder 12: 29)
    - 1958-1959 (Folder 12: 30)
    - 1960 (Folder 12: 31)
    - 1961-1962 (Folder 12: 32)
  - Vol'skaia, V., 1964-1965 (Folder 12: 33)
  - Volzhanin O.A., (Israelson, I.), 1939 (Folder 12: 34)
  - Voronovich, N., undated (Folder 12: 35)
  - Wagman, Max, 1955 (Folder 12: 36)
  - Wallace, Schuler, 1945 (Folder 12: 37)
  - Walne, Florence, 1944 (Folder 12: 38)
  - Walsh, Richard J., 1945 (Folder 12: 39)
  - Walsh, Warren B., 1948-1949 (Folder 12: 40)
  - Wang, Sabine, 1951 (Folder 12: 41)
  - Wanner, Lewis D., undated (Folder 12: 42)
  - Warburg, Edward M., 1964 (Folder 12: 43)
  - Ways, Max, 1959 (Folder 12: 44)
  - Weinbaum, M., 1942-1968 (Folder 12: 45)
  - Weinreich, Max, 1941-1949 (Folder 12: 46)
  - Weitzman, C., 1947 (Folder 12: 47)
  - Welles, Samuel G., 1947 (Folder 12: 48)
  - White, Laura A., 1945 (Folder 12: 49)
  - Wieck, Fred, 1947 (Folder 12: 50)
  - Wiggins, Henry H., 1947 (Folder 12: 51)
  - Willey, Fay, 1967 (Folder 12: 52)
  - Williams, Robert C., 1965 (Folder 12: 53)
  - Wise, Stephen S., 1940-1941 (Folder 12: 54)
  - Wissotsky, A., 1946-1947 (Folder 12: 55)
  - Wolberg, A., 1967-1968 (Box-folder 13: 1)
  - Wolf, Bertram D., 1966 (Folder 13: 2)
  - Wolin, S., 1945 (Folder 13: 3)
  - Wolossoff, B., 1946-1963
    - 1946 (Folder 13: 4)
    - 1947-1949 (Folder 13: 5)
    - 1950-1952 (Folder 13: 6)
    - 1953-1954 (Folder 13: 7)
    - 1956-1963 (Folder 13: 8)
  - Woolbert, Robert G., 1944-1946 (Folder 13: 9)
  - Workmen's Circle, The, 1942-1944 (Folder 13: 10)
  - Wormuth, Francis D., 1956 (Folder 13: 11)
  - Woytinsky, W.S. and E.S., 1938-1961 (Folder 13: 12)
  - Wyrouboff, B.B., 1960 (Folder 13: 13)
  - Yale University Press, 1942, 1968 (Folder 13: 14)
  - Yanovskii, B., 1941 (Folder 13: 15)
  - Yarmolinsky, A., 1953 (Folder 13: 16)
  - Yasser, Joseph, 1942 (Folder 13: 17)
  - Zabejinski, G.B., 1959 (Folder 13: 18)
  - Zaitsev, Boris, 1945-1969 (Folder 13: 19)
  - Zasgwell, undated (Folder 13: 20)
  - Zeeler, V.M., 1949-1955 (Folder 13: 21)
  - Zeluk, O., 1938 (Folder 13: 22)
  - Zenzinov, V., 1923-1951
    - undated (Folder 13: 23)
    - 1923-1934 (Folder 13: 24)
    - 1941-1943 (Folder 13: 25)
    - 1944 (Folder 13: 26)
    - 1945 (Folder 13: 27)
    - 1946-1950 (Folder 13: 28)
    - 1951 (Folder 13: 29)
  - Zernova, S., 1955 (Folder 13: 30)
  - Zetlin, M., 1939-1961 (Folder 13: 31)
  - Zhaba, Sergei, 1960 (Folder 13: 32)
  - Zhakob, Tati'ana, 1954-1965 (Folder 13: 33)
  - Zharikh, 1941 (Folder 13: 34)
  - Zherby, L., 1963 (Folder 13: 35)
  - Zilberger, K., 1939 (Folder 13: 36)
  - Zitron, J., 1955 (Folder 13: 37)
  - Znamensky, T., 1953-1969 (Folder 13: 38)
  - Zolotarev, V., 1959 (Folder 13: 39)
  - Zveden, A., 1942 (Folder 13: 40)
  - Zwibak, Jacques, undated (Folder 13: 41)
- Biographical File, 1925-1995.
  Arranged by physical form
  - Newspaper clippings on Vishniak's seventy-fifth, eightieth and eighty-fifth birthdays (Folder 13: 42)
  - Archives, notes, reviews and responses to Dun' Proshlomu and Sovremmenya Zapiski by M. Vishniak
  - Notebook, contains excerpts of I. Fonfaminsky' letters and Sowremennye Zapiski archives, 1927-1929 (Folder 13: 43)
  - Correspondence, 1925-1969
    - undated (Folder 13: 44)
    - 1925-1935. (Folder 13: 45)
      Copies from Lilly Library Manuscripts Collections
    - 1954 (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - 1955 (Folder 14: 2)
    - 1956 (Folder 14: 3)
    - 1957 (Folder 14: 4)
    - 1958 (Folder 14: 5)
    - 1959 (Folder 14: 6)
    - 1961-1969 (Folder 14: 7)
  - Press clippings
    - 1927-1933 (Folder 14: 8)
    - 1954-1958 (Folder 14: 9)
  - Ekonomicheskoe nasledie russkogo zarubezh'ia. Kniga 2 Mark Vishniak, by Eduard B. Koritskii, Saint Petersburg, 1995 (Folder 14: 10)
- Speeches and Writings, 1918-1970.
  - Literary endeavors and articles clippings
    - From newspapers Dni, Berlin, Novaia Rossiia, and Posledniia Novosti, Paris (Folder 14: 11)
      - 1919-1936
      - 1919-1936 (Box-folder 15: 1-2)
    - From newspaper Segodnia, Riga, 1936-1938 (Folder 15: 3)
    - From magazine Novaia Rossiia, Paris, 1939-1940 (Folder 15: 4)
    - From magazines Sotzialisticheskii Vestnik, Slavic (Folder 15: 5)
    - Review, New York, Communist Affairs, Los Angeles, Time, 1943-1969
    - From newspaper Russkaia Mysl', Paris
      - 1955-1966 (Folder 15: 6-7)
      - 1955-1966 (Box-folder 16: 1-2)
    - From newspaper Novoye Russkoe Slovo (Folder 16: 3-6)
    - New York, 1947-1967
  - Drafts of articles, 1940-1970. (Folder 16: 7-11)
    Includes two notes-books
  - Published articles, 1942-1966 (Folder 16: 12-15)
  - Published articles, 1942-1966 (Box-folder 17: 1-3)
  - Reprints of Vishniak's articles, 1922-1958
    - 1922-1943 (Folder 17: 4)
    - 1942-1945 (Folder 17: 5)
    - 1946-1948 (Folder 17: 6)
    - 1949-1950 (Folder 17: 7)
    - 1952-1954 (Folder 17: 8)
    - 1955-1956 (Folder 17: 9)
    - 1957 (Folder 17: 10)
    - 1958 (Folder 17: 11)
    - 1959-1967 (Folder 17: 12)
  - Typescripts of talks to USSR through "Radio Liberty," New-York - Munich, 1956-1961 (Folder 17: 13)
  - Transfer of Population, typescript, undated (Box-folder 18: 1-2)
  - International Convention against Anti-Semitism, typescript, 1946
    - Chapters 1-2 (Folder 18: 3)
    - Chapters 3-4 (Folder 18: 4)
    - Chapters 5-6 (Folder 18: 5)
    - Reviews (Folder 18: 6)
  - International Protection of minorities through the League of Nations, undated (Folder 18: 7)
  - The Legal Status of the Stateless, 1945
    - Archives, notes (Folder 18: 8)
    - Original in Russian (Folder 18: 9-11)
    - Translation in English (Folder 18: 12-15)
  - The Right of Asylum, 1955 (Folder 18: 16)
  - Lenin, original manuscript, 1932.
    In Russian
    - Chapters 1-3 (Folder 18: 17)
    - Chapters 4-6 (Folder 18: 18)
    - Chapters 7-8 (Box-folder 19: 1)
    - Chapters 9-10 (Folder 19: 2)
    - Chapters 11-14 (Folder 19: 3)
    - Reviews (Folder 19: 4)
  - Léon Blum, Flammarion, 1932. (Folder 19: 5)
    Copy sighed by Léon Blum to M. Vishniak
  - "World Association and Organized Labor", 1943. (Folder 19: 6)
    Typescript
- Subject File, 1917-1953.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject
  - New York Group of Russian Socialist Revolutionary Party
    - General, 1932. (Folder 19: 7)
      Includes research material on Russian Revolution
    - Vasilii Sukhomlin case, 1941-1942 (Folder 19: 8)
  - New York Party of Socialist-Revolutionaries, excerpts. Includes estimony of Vera Gotz during interrogation of V. V. Doukhomilin and M. L. Slonim, September 2, 1917- January 30, 1918 (Folder 19: 9)
  - Russian Imperial Duma and All Russian Continental Assembly stenographic and historical accounts, 1906, 1958 (Folder 19: 10)
  - Russian Social Revolutionary, Public record office connections with the German Foreign Ministry, 1916-1917 (Folder 19: 11)
  - Material related to Vladimir Zenzinov interstate estate, New York County, 1953 (Folder 19: 12)
- Photographs, 1929-1945.
  Arranged chronologically
  - General. (Folder 19: 13)
  - Mark Vishniak photo and Time Incorporated identification card, undated (Folder 19: 14)
  - Avksent'ev, N.D., undated (Folder 19: 15)
  - Editors of Russkie Vedomosti, Moscow's newspaper in Paris, 1929 (Folder 19: 16)
  - Kerensky, A., negative and sketch, 1945 (Folder 19: 17)
  - Miscellany (Folder 19: 18)